Daniel Pinedo

Introduction_

I have extensive education and experience as a social science statistical analyst and consultant. My MA degree in Organizational Behavior and Evaluation included units in intermediate statistics, regression analysis, ANOVA, and categorical data analysis. Evaluation coursework included applied statistics. I audited graduate mathematical units in network theory and have subsequently completed projects for NSF external program evaluators using social network analysis. I have taken several certification courses in statistics and data science using R and Python.

My work experience as Principal of Kinesis Consulting and Lecturer at Mount Saint Mary's University included extensive data analysis, methods and survey design, cross-disciplinary and intra-disciplinary collaboration, project and team management, evaluation report writing, peer-reviewed publication, stakeholder dissemination of findings through presentations and executive summaries for non-technical audiences, and conference proceedings.

I am an expert level programmer in R language, with extensive experience using Python, JavaScript, and SPSS for data analysis and visualization.

keywords: statistics, R, shiny, python, javascript, spss, data visualization, social science, regression, ANOVA, categorical analysis, social network analysis, survey design, survey analysis, program evaluation, consultant, analyst, project management, personnel management

Education_

Claremont Graduate University

Claremont, CA

MA Psychology

Sep 2018 - May 2020

• Concentrations in Organizational Behavior & Evaluation

Sofia University

Palo Alto, CA

MA Psychology

Sep 2010 - May 2013

Concentration in Clinical Psychology

Naropa University

Boulder, CO

BA TRADITIONAL EASTERN ARTS

Sep 2008 - May 2010

• Student Government: Treasurer

Professional Experience _

Sep 2019 - Mar 2022	Principal, Kinesis Consulting (20 hours / week)
Nov 2018 - Jun 2020	Consultant, Accenture Plc, CGU Talent Innovation Lab (20 hours / week)
Sep 2016 - May 2018	Lecturer (and academic counselor), Psychology, Mount Saint Mary's University (full time)
Aug 2014 - Jul 2015	Clinician, Sovereign Health Group, adult partial inpatient rehabilitation center (full time)
Aug 2013 - Jul 2014	Clinician, Mind Body Awareness Project, adolescent drug and alcohol counseling (20 hours / week)
Aug 2012 - Jul 2013	Clinician, San Mateo County juvenile detention center, forensic psychological evaluation (20 hours / week)
Aug 2011 - Jul 2012	Clinician, Lifemoves family homeless shelter, individual & family therapy (20 hours / week)
2002 - 2008	IT Consultant, network engineering specialist (full time)

Evaluation

Kinesis Consulting

Phoenixville, PA

ROLE: PRINCIPAL Sep 2019 - Mar 2022

- Statistical consultation including social science methodology, visualization, and presentation in support of policy & planning
 analysis and program evaluation for the scientific community. Focus is on methodological innovation for evaluation in support
 of climate change mitigation and resilience infrastructure projects. Examples of recent projects:
- Survey analysis and presentation for external program evaluation in NSF Directorate for Geosciences
- Mixed method / Social network analysis for external program evaluation in NSF Division of Undergraduate Education
- Social network analyses for external program evaluation in NSF Office of Integrative Activities.

Consulting

Accenture Talent Innovation Lab

Claremont, CA

Nov 2018 - Jun 2020

ROLES: CONSULTANT, PROJECT MANAGER, TEAM LEAD

- Global HR / Recruitment Transformation Research & Development Lab
- Managed project deliverable content and translated research into business cases.
- Consulted with stakeholder managers on organizational behavior, management, statistics, research methods, interviewing, and focus groups.
- · Led project teams.
- Managed performance and career development.
- Managed project timelines, milestones, personnel time, and budgeting.
- Trained team on client on-boarding, acculturation, pitching and public speaking, time management, technical mentoring, and cross-functional communication.
- Created interviewing/hiring criteria as member of Recruitment and Selection Committee.
- Served as resource for strategy insights and revenue ideas.
- High-impact project examples include:
- Future workplace job redesign research and market analysis for account executive role
- Documentation sprint to prepare final presentation of vetted global employee selection and assessment model
- Validation of scoring measure for behavioral interview
- Development of values-based assessment prototype
- Selection assessment design prototype
- Leadership model synthesis and design

Claremont Graduate University

Claremont, CA

Sep 2018 - May 2020

DEPT OF BEHAVIORAL AND ORGANIZATIONAL SCIENCES

- Evaluation plan for North America regional HR client organization Arup
- Intensive organizational behavior assessment center for Getty Leadership Center
- Organizational culture project for private, family-owned property management firm
- Organizational behavior project for ICM Partners creative talent agency undergoing HR restructuring
- Competition: BCG Datathon team leader for invitation only data science business case competition

Teaching_

2017-2018	Academic Counseling, 10-15 students per semester	MSMU
SP 2018	Basic Quantitative Research Methods, Lecture, Lecturer	
	Basic Quantitative Research Methods, Lab, Lecturer	
FA 2017	Basic Quantitative Research Methods, Lecture (Two Sections), Lecturer	
	Basic Quantitative Research Methods, Lab (Two Sections), Lecturer	
SP 2017	Basic Quantitative Research Methods, Lecture, Adjunct	
	Basic Quantitative Research Methods, Lab, Adjunct	
	Industrial & Organizational Psychology, Adjunct	
FA 2016	Basic Quantitative Research Methods, Lecture, Adjunct	
	Basic Quantitative Research Methods, Lab, Adjunct	
	Social Psychology, Adjunct	
SP 2016	Basic Quantitative Research Methods, Lecture, Adjunct	
	Basic Quantitative Research Methods, Lab, Adjunct	
SP 2012	Doctoral Seminar: Qualitative Research, Teaching Assistant	Sofia
FA 2012	Special Topic: Dissertation Research and Writing Support, Teaching Assistant	

_		•		
Рπ	hI	lica [.]	tı∩	nc

PUBLISHED

Himelstein, S., Saul, S., Garcia-Romeu, A., & **Pinedo, D.** (2014). Mindfulness training as an intervention for substance user incarcerated adolescents: A pilot grounded theory study. *Substance Use & Misuse.*

Kaczmarczyk, L., & **Pinedo, D.** (2021). Getting things done in data intensive inter-campus research initiatives: A social network analysis approach to understanding and building effective relationships between researchers and other university employees. In *Proceedings of the 2021 American Society for Engineering Education Annual Conference & Exposition* (Vol. 26)

Presentations _____

INVITED TALKS

Spring 2018, Fall 2017. ⁺ Coordination of symposium and opening speech on topic of importance of promoting undergraduate research and representation of women in STEM. Invited talk: Undergraduate research symposium, Mount Saint Mary's University, Los Angeles, CA

CONTRIBUTED PRESENTATIONS

- Himelstein, S., & **Pinedo, D.** (2013). Empowering communities: An intensive mindfulness training in a retreat setting for college-bound adolescents and college-aged tutors. [Meditation Retreat]. Redwood Glen Summer Camp; Loma Mar, CA.
- Himelstein, S., **Pinedo, D.**, & Mousseau, A. (2013). *Mindfulness training for educators: An intensive training at the Lakota Nation at Pine Ridge.* [Inservice Training]. Little Wound High School; Kyle, SD.
- Kaczmarczyk, L., & **Pinedo, D.** (July 2021). *Getting things done in data intensive inter-campus research initiatives: A social network analysis approach to understanding and building effective relationships between researchers and other university employees.* [Poster Presentation]. The 2021 American Society for Engineering Education Annual Conference & Exposition. Long Beach, CA.
- **Pinedo, D.**, Gutierrez, G., & Tinoco, C. (2013). Assessment, prevention, and discussion of health disparities in local Native American populations [Continuing Education Training]. Health Services Building, San Mateo, CA.

Service

2016	Wilshire Detective Division, Volunteer	LAPD
2014	Venice Neighborhood Council, Member, Neighborhood Committee	CA
2009	Student Government, Treasurer	Naropa

Professional Development _____

2020 - 2021 Data Scientist with Python, Certificate

DataCamp

Data Scientist with R, Certificate

Data Visualization with R, Certificate

Designing and Analyzing Clinical Trials in R, Certificate

Machine Learning Scientist with Python, Certificate

Machine Learning Scientist with R, Certificate

Network Analysis with R, Certificate

R Programmer, Certificate

Shiny Fundamentals with R, Certificate

Spatial Data with R, Certificate

Survival Analysis in R, Certificate

Statistician with R, Certificate

Time Series with R, Certificate

⁺ mentored undergraduates